Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 813 Private Sanitation Union: Leonard Krouner Files WAG.053
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 813 Private Sanitation Union: Leonard Krouner Files
1975-1984, (Bulk 1982-1983)
1982-1983
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Brotherhood of Teamsters. Local 813, Private Sanitation Union
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
WAG.053
2 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
In 1982 International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 813, Private Sanitation Union filed a complaint with the National Labor Relations Board against Carnival Carting, Inc. and associated companies and individuals for unfair labor practices. The union charged that the employers cited failed to bargain in good faith, among other complaints. The employers countered with allegations of intimidation and other abuses by the union before and during the December 1981 New York City private sanitation-men's strike. After lengthy and complex proceedings and the case was settled on appeal to the Supreme Court of the State of New York. The case files and legal research of Albany attorney Leonard W. Krouner, who represented the employers, include briefs, transcripts, exhibits, clippings, and handwritten case notes.
Custodial History
Leonard Krouner originally donated these files to the Labor-Management Documentation Center at Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, which in turn transferred them to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, NYU in 1986.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 813, Private Sanitation Union, was chartered in September 1951 with jurisdiction over workers in New York City's private sanitation industry.
Leonard Krouner was one of the attorneys who represented Carnival Carting, Inc. and its Executive Vice-President Richard ("Rick") Carnivale in a case that the union brought before the National Labor Relations Board in 1982. The union charged that the employers failed to bargain in good faith (and other related charges), and the employers countered with a barrage of allegations of intimidation and fraud on the part of the union. The context of the dispute was the bitter seventeen-day sanitation strike that began December 1, 1981 and left New York City covered in 100,000 tons of garbage. Two thousand members of Local 813 struck against 480 carting companies, three of which, Carnival Carting, S.W.C. (Statewide Carting Disposal) and Anchor Waste became involved in the NLRB disputes.
After a tangled series of proceedings, which included charges of malfeasance on the part of several judges and arbitrators, Krouner's clients appealed to the Supreme Court of the State of New York in 1983. The respondents named were Bernard Adelstein, Secretary Treasurer of Local 813 and leading negotiator for the union during the strike; employees of the Tudor Carting Company party to a collective bargaining agreement with Local 813; the General and Special Counsel for Local 813; New York City officials authorized to collect judgment; any person or legal entity holding any property of Carnival Carting under legal restraint by Local 813; and the State Mediation Board. Several issues were finally decided in favor of the appellants.
Scope and Content Note
The National Labor Relations Board briefs, transcripts and exhibits make up the bulk of the collection and are numbered in chronological order (Box 1, folders 1-12). These are followed by briefs, transcripts and other legal documents related to cases in the appeals division of the National Labor Relations Board and the Supreme Court of the State of New York. Topical research files follow; these include background material on Carnival Carting, legal issues, IBT Local 813, and various witnesses. The Research series also includes a clippings file created by Vito A. Turso, Public Information and Community Affairs Deputy Commissioner, Department of Sanitation, City of New York.
Arrangement
In Series I National Labor Relations Board litigation files, appeals and exhibits are arranged chronologically, and are followed by files for the Supreme Court of the State of New York (appeal). Series II is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Organized into 2 series: I, Litigation, 1982-1983; II. Research Files, 1975-1984.
Missing Title
I, Litigation, 1982-1983.
II, Research Files, 1975-1984.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives at Cornell University, 1986. The accession number associated with this gift is 1986.021.
Transcripts.; Sanitation Workers Strike |z New York (State) |z New York, 1981.; Research (document genres).; Sanitation workers -- New York (State) -- New York.; Clippings (information artifacts); Briefs (legal documents); New York (N.Y.).; Carnival Carting, Inc.; Adelstein, Bernard; Barretti, Phil; International Brotherhood of Teamsters; International Brotherhood of Teamsters. Local 813, Private Sanitation Union; Krouner, Leonard; Carnivale, Richard; Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
- Series I: Litigation, 1982-1983.
  - National Labor Relations Board (NLRB): Carnival Carting, SWC, and Anchor Waste v. Local 813, Private Sanitation Union, IBT (29-CA-9770; 9396) (Carnival Carting v. Local 813) (I), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (II), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (III), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (IV), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (V), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (VI), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (VII), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (VIII), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (IX), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (X), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (XI), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (XII), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - NLRB Appeals Division: Carnival Carting v. Local 813, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - NLRB Appeals Division: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (Exhibits), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (General Council's Exhibits), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - NLRB: Carnival Carting v. Local 813 (Respondent's Exhibits), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Supreme Court of the State of New York, Appellate Division (SCNY): Carnival Carting, Richard Carnivale, S. W. C., Security Haulage and Anchor Waste v. Bernard Adelstein, personally and as Secretary-Treasurer of the I. B. T., Tudor Carting, et al. (Carnival Carting v. Adelstein) (I), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - SCNY: Carnival Carting v. Adelstein (II), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series II: Research Files, 1975-1981.
  - Research: Carnival Carting, 1977-1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Research: Carnival Carting (plans for future litigation), undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Research: Clippings, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Research: Clippings (Vito Turso Files), 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Research: Legal, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Research: Local 813, 1978-1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Research: Witnesses, 1978-1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)